Safal Kumar Biswas

 ♦ Mohakhali, Dhaka
 ☑ safalbiswas005@gamil.com
 ↓ 01781 036031
 ♦ My Portfolio

■ Codeforces in Safal Biswas 🔾 safal-biswas

About Me

I'm a competitive programmer with several years of experience with excelling on platforms like Codeforces & LeetCode. Also possess a strong foundation in front-end technologies for creating visually appealing, interactive, and user-friendly websites. Strengths include rapid problem-solving, adaptability to various coding environments, and a commitment to continuous improvement.

Experience

Web Developer Intern (Remote)

Kolkata, India Sept 2024 – Oct 2024

CodSoft

- o Developed dynamic components using React.js front-end library & enhancing website interactivity.
- o Managed data & performed CRUD operations using MongoDB & MySQL databases.
- Integrated external APIs to process & display JSON data, enabling real-time information updates.
- Tasks: Built portfolio & landing pages, a quiz website, and a JavaScript-based game, showcasing a range of design and functionality skills.

Front End Developer Trainee

Rangpur, Bangladesh June 2024 - Aug 2024

Creative item

- Experienced in building interactive web pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Understand and apply concepts of responsive design and browser compatibility.
- Completed projects & built simple websites using React.JS and Tailwind CSS.

Education

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

Feb 2019 - May 2024

B.Sc.Engg. in Electrical & Computer Engineering

 Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Data Structure & Algorithms, Data Base Systems, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Computer Networks & Machine Learning.

Projects

Agency Website for Creativeitem

link 🗹

- Designed and developed a sleek, responsive website for a corporate agency, featuring key sections. The site
 includes interactive elements to engage users effectively.
- o Tools Used: React.JS and Tailwind CSS

Minesweeper Game

link \square

- Developed a Minesweeper game using JavaScript with dynamic board generation, random mine placement, cell revealing, flagging, and win/lose conditions, plus a timer and score tracking.
- Tools Used: HTML, CSS & JavaScript

Flappy Bird Game

link 🗹

- Created a traditional Flappy Bird game for PC with scoring, difficulty levels & supports multiple profiles.
- o Tools Used: Python

Technologies

Languages: C, C++, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, NoSQL & Arduino

Technologies: Tailwind CSS, React.JS, Node.JS & MongoDB